Jitendra Sen

Mob:8982443676 e-mail: jitendrasen307@gmail.com

Address: Jimmi Tower Kopar khairane Navi Mumbai

Objective:

I am employed as a Software Engineer, with 3.3 Year of experience, post graduate degree in computer science. I have passion for programming; I have worked on multiple projects using object-oriented programming tools and have been recognized at the company.

Professional Summary:

Technically Sophisticated Professional with 2.9 years of experience in developing Web and Enterprise Applications in J2EE environment.

In-depth knowledge of the object-oriented programming & development of J2EE technologies.

Worked extensively on Core Java, JDBC, Servlet, JSP, Spring, Hibernate jasper report.

Proficient in developing web application with MVC architecture using **Spring Framework**.

Good knowledge on database such as MySql.

Strong analytical skills and a demonstrated ability to handle multiple tasks as well as ability to work independently or in a team.

Experience Summary:

IT Vendor	Position	Role	Period of service
Takira Solutions Pvt Ltd	Software Developer	Software Development Engineer	Nov 2018-present
Bizlem Pvt Ltd	Software Developer	Software Development	Feb 2018 – Nov 2018
Shreesoft Technology	Software De. + Intern	Software Dev.+Intern(Trainee) 6 Month	Nov 2015 – Jan 2018

Academic Qualification:

- I have completed **Master of Computer Applications** (2013-2016) from School of Computer Science &Information Technology, (DAVV) with **50.04%**
- Bachelor of computer science (cs) from Swami Vivekanand College of Professional Studies, in Barkatullah University Bhopal 2012 with 63.00%
- Higher Secondary from M.P Board in 2008 with 50%
- High School from M.P Board in 2006 with 49.6%

Technical Skills:

Operating System : Windows XP/7/8 Programming Languages: Java, MySQL,

Presentation Layer : JSP, Servlet, Ajax, Html, Jquery, jasper report

Data Access Layer : JDBC, Hibernate
Frameworks : Hibernate, Spring
Databases : MySQL 5.0.
Server : Apache Tomcat8,

Tools : Eclipse

Other Tools : Maven, Log4j, SQLYOG

Delivered Projects:

Project 1:

Project Name : DMS

Technology : Spring and Hibernate, My Sql Database

Tool : Eclipse Maven, Log4j, SQLYOG, SQL Workbench, jasper report

Project Description:

Different multi-Company System (DMS) this project use to different Company user and Document type. DMS software integrates all facets of an operation -including product planning, development, manufacturing, sales and marketing in a single database, application and user interface

Role and Responsibilities:

Effective involvement in planning meeting and coordinate with the Technical Lead on current programming tasks.

Developing the Code as per the requirements and collaborate with other programmers to design and implement features.

Debugging the issues related to code and unit testing.

Upheld program quality and delivery standards in developing software solutions.

Delivered Projects:

Project 2:

Project Name : Carrot Rule

Technology : Apache.sling,JCR ()

Project Description:

Carrot Rule is all based product Focusing are Business process Transformation carrot Rule automatically calculates the increment or commission of the employees is use time. one can use complex scenarios to calculate monthly quarterly and year increment. There is no used doing complex calculation in carrot rules.

Role and Responsibilities:

Creating Apache sling Node.. Create API &&. Rest-full

• Drl class rule generate.

Delivered Projects:

Project 3:

Project Name : SoftCoder

Technology : Spring ,Hibernate ,MYSQL

Project Description:

Soft-coder which is provide online tutorials, Training courses, IT blogs, Academic project,

Documents. It also manages student's record for admin like registration module, managing course and tutorials etc. The project is a web based application for automating all the activities of the college starting from student registration to student examination and result generate on this application deployed on college server

Role and Responsibilities:

Creating classes and method implementation..

Developing the Code as per the requirements and collaborate with other programmers to design and implement features.

Debugging the issues related to code.

Personal Information

Marital Status Language known Hobbies : married
Date of Birth : Hindi, English

Permanent Address : listening Music, Reading

: 04 Jun 1991

: 163/12 Village Bijlone Sehore (M.P)

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above written information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date:

Place: Mumbai Jitendra Sen